submissionmonster.com 2019-01-16

# Submission Monster: Search Engine Submission and Marketing Services

## Privacy Policy Overview

This Privacy Policy applies where we, GreenWave Online Inc., acts as a data controller or data processor with regard to all individuals including EU individuals under the General Data Protection Regulation ("GDPR").

#### Data Collection and Usage

There are two types of data we collect, information collected automatically "usage data" and information you provide to us "service data".

When you visit our websites we collect usage data such as (but not limited to) IP address, geo-location information, device type, operating system and Internet browser type, referral URL and standard web log data. This usage data may be processed for our legitimate interests namely monitoring, and improving our website and services.

When you voluntarily use tools or services on our website we may collect service data such as (but not limited to) Name, Email Address and Website URL. This service data may be processed to provide our services, maintain a record of those services, and to communicate with you based on your consent.

In the case of paid services additional personal data such as your contact and billing details are processed by our Third Party payment service provider, PayPal.

Submission Monster reserves the right to use the contact information collected with your consent during site submission to deliver notices regarding changes or updates to our service, to provide free sample newsletters, to inform you of additions to the GreenWave Online Network of web sites, or to send announcements and carefully screened offers and information from our partners.

With the exception of autoresponse messages which are sent when you sign-up for our service and contain important account information, you may remove yourself from any or all other notice and announcement mailings at anytime using the unsubscribe methods provided in those mailings. Any mailing received from our company is clearly identified and includes at least 2 methods to remove yourself from future mailings. Should you encounter problems in this regard, contact: inquiry[at]submissionmonster.com. Our turnaround time for responding to unsubscribe requests is generally 24 hours.

#### Data Sharing

When you voluntarily use tools or services that involve publication of your information on our website this data may be available via the internet. We cannot prevent the use (or misuse) of such information by others.

When you voluntarily use tools or services that involve submission of your information to third parties, we act as an agent for you to provide your information to a third party for a specific purpose. Each third party will act as a data controller in that instance.

Data may be shared if it is required to comply with requests from courts, law enforcement agencies, regulatory agencies, and other public and government authorities.

#### Cookies

Cookies are only used on the Submission Monster site for login management.

#### Security

Your personal information is stored in a protected directory. Access is restricted to Submission Monster staff.

#### Additional Rights

You have the right to request the data we have stored, as well as the right to have that data erased and to withdraw consent to further process your data.

#### Changes to this Privacy Policy

Submission Monster may amend this policy from time to time. If significant changes are made in the way your personal information is used, we will post a prominent announcement on our site notifying you of the change.

#### Questions or Suggestions

Questions or suggestions may be sent to: inquiry[at]submissionmonster.com
